[Music]
Amen. Amen. Uh happy Sabbath everyone.
Welcome to Living Manor online. Uh we
have a um uh by the grace of God uh a
message that
um
is very needed
and by the grace of God will bring dry
bones together.
Um praise God for that opening trailer
and we are about to get into the word uh
today. So, put a one in the chat if you
are ready. Ready to uh to eat.
The title of the message today.
Left Jesus.
Right Jesus.
Right Jesus. Let's pray. Heavenly
Father,
please speak
to your people
in Jesus name we pray. Amen.
We're going to go to the screen.
We'll go to our first slide. Um,
please make sure that you share this
link as we begin this message. Let
people know that the sermon has begun
and uh and that we're going to eat and
um we're going to get into this word.
Left Jesus,
right? Jesus.
In the book of first kings chapter 3
uh verse 5, the Bible
records these words in Gibian. The Lord
appeared to Solomon in a dream by night.
And God said, "Ask what I shall give
thee." And Solomon said, "Thou hast
showed unto thy servant David, my
father, great mercy, according as he as
he has walked before thee in truth
and in righteousness, and in uprightness
of heart with thee." And thou has given
him, thou has kept for him this great
kindness, that thou has given him a son
to sit on his throne as it is this day.
And now, oh Lord my God, thou has made
thy servant king instead of David my
father. And I am but a child. I know not
how to go out or come in. And thy
servant is in the midst of thy people,
which thou hast chosen, a great people
that cannot be numbered, nor counted for
multitude.
Give therefore thy servant an
understanding heart to judge thy people,
that I may discern
between good and evil. For who is able
to judge this, thy so great a people?
And the speech pleased the Lord that
Solomon had asked this thing.
And God said unto him, because thou hast
asked this thing, and has not asked for
thyself long life, neither hast asked
riches for thyself, nor hast asked the
life of thine enemies, but has asked for
thyself understanding to discern
judgment.
Behold,
I have done according to thy works. Lo,
I have given thee a wise and
understanding heart, so that there was
none like thee before, neither after
thee shall any arise like unto thee.
And I I've also given thee that which
thou has not asked, both riches and
honor,
so that there shall not be any among the
kings like unto thee all thy days. And
if thou will walk in my ways, to keep my
statutes and my commandments, as thy
father David did walk,
then I will lengthen thy days.
And Solomon awoke, and behold, it was a
dream. And he came to Jerusalem, and
stood before the ark of the covenant of
the Lord, and offered up a burnt
offering, and offered peace offerings,
and made a feast to all his servants.
We are living in a time
in which wisdom
is required.
Wisdom has always been required for
God's people.
But especially
as we come closer and closer to the
second coming of the Lord, wisdom is
more needed than ever.
The Bible tells us in Daniel 12:3, for
example, it says here, "Many will be and
they that be wise shall shine as the
brightness of the firmament, and they
that turn many to righteousness as the
stars
forever."
Daniel 12 10 or 12:10 rather
says many shall be purified
and made white and tried but the wicked
shall do wickedly and none of the wicked
shall understand
but the wise
shall understand.
We are living in a time where wisdom
is needed.
Wisdom allows us to discern between good
and evil. You see Solomon in his prayer,
he's asking the Lord for wisdom so that
he can discern between good and evil.
And in today's day, as evil is
progressing, as evil is growing, we need
wisdom to discern what is good and what
is evil.
Especially at the end of time where we
understand that the greatest deception
will be pulled upon the whole world.
Spoken of in Revelation 13:14
where it says that this power deceiveth
them that dwell on the earth by the
means of those miracles which he had
power to do in the sight of the beast.
Saying to them that dwell on the earth
that they should make an image to the
beast which had a wound by the sword and
did live. We understand here that
whatever this power is which is
ultimately a satanic power which will
ultimately culminate
with Satan himself appearing as Jesus.
We are going to need wisdom
to know the difference between goodness
and error,
between truth,
light and darkness,
between the real Jesus
and the counterfeit Jesus.
Wisdom will be required. And so the book
of James chapter 1 tells us gives us
encouraging words. It actually says,
"If any of you lack wisdom, let him ask
of God that giveth to all men libery and
uprath not, and it shall be given him."
Just as Solomon asked for wisdom, we too
may ask for wisdom. And the Bible says
that God will give it. The other reason
wisdom is needed, we're told in
Proverbsap 1:7, "The fear of the Lord is
the beginning of knowledge, but fools
despise wisdom and instruction."
Wisdom is going to be required not only
for us to stand at the end of time.
for us to be able to discern between
that which is good and that which is
evil. But wisdom is the beginning of the
fear of the Lord or the fear of the Lord
is the beginning of knowledge or wisdom.
In order for us to stand in the last
days, we're going to need wisdom. We're
going to need wisdom. and put up one in
the chat if you raise your hand today to
say, "Lord, give me wisdom." Those who
don't have wisdom, the Bible likens in
Matthew 7 26 with these words.
And everyone that hear these sayings of
mine, and doeth them not, shall be
likened unto a not a wise man, but a
foolish man, which built his house upon
the sand. and the rain descended and the
floods came and the winds blew and beat
upon that house and it fell and great
was the fall of it.
We're going to need wisdom in the last
days. Not only to discern the true
Christ from the false Christ,
but even to discern true Christianity
from false Christianity. The Bible tells
us
uh in Matthew chapter chapter uh 7 that
not all who say Lord Lord
will enter into the kingdom of heaven.
The Bible says that only those who do
the will of God will enter into the
kingdom of heaven. So in essence in the
last days especially there will be a
counterfeit Christianity, a counterfeit
Jesus.
And if we don't have the wisdom, we will
not be able to discern between that
which is good and that which is bad,
that which is light and that which is
darkness. Are y'all with me so far?
In light of this,
the verses we just read in First Kings
sets us up for the actual demonstration
of why wisdom is needed. Let's go back
to the screen and we will pick up where
we left off. We're now in verse 16. So
remember Solomon has
woken up. It was a dream that he had and
in the dream God has given him wisdom.
He goes to Jerusalem and he's standing
he's standing
uh um
giving up or or they're giving up
offerings to God as a celebration. The
ark of the covenant is mentioned. Please
keep that in mind. And then we read this
event taking place. The Bible says,
"Then came there two women that were
harlots
unto the king and stood before him. And
the one woman said,"Oh my Lord, I and
this woman dwell in one house, and I was
delivered of a child with her in the
house. And it came to pass the third day
after that I was delivered, that this
woman was delivered also, and we were
together. And there was no stranger with
us in the house, save we too in the
house."
And this woman's child died in the night
because she overlaid it. And she arose
at midnight and took my son from beside
me while thine handmmaid slept and laid
it in her bosom and laid her dead child
in my bosom.
And when I arose in the morning to give
my child suck, behold, it was dead. But
when I considered it in the morning,
behold, it was not my son which I did
bear. And the other woman said, "Nay,
but the living is my son, and the dead
is thy son." And this said, "No, but the
dead is thy son, and the living is my
son." Thus they spake before the king.
Then said the king, "The one saith, this
is my son that liveth, and thy son is
dead." And the other saith, nay, but thy
son is the dead, and my son is the
living. And the king said, "Bring me a
sword." And they brought a sword before
the king.
And the king said, "Divide
the living child into two,
and give half to the one,
and half to the other."
Then spake the woman, whose the living
child was unto the king, for her bowels
yearned upon her son. And she said, "Oh
my lord, give her the living child, and
in no wise, slay it." But the other
said, "Let it be neither mine nor thine,
but divide it." Then said the king, Then
the king answered and said, "Give her
the living child, and in no wise slay
it, she is the mother thereof."
How many of you are familiar with this
story?
You've read this story before. You've
heard this story before.
In this story,
two women come before the king.
And in the story, they both are claiming
that the son belongs to them.
Let me say it again.
They both claim that the son the son
the son belongs to them.
Somebody is not telling the truth.
And the one who is not telling the truth
is acting so well that Solomon in all
his wisdom cannot discern who is lying
and who is telling the truth.
So the woman says, "My child, I I went
to sleep. This woman's child, she she
she
smothered her child basically and the
child died." And then she switched her
child for my child
and this is an injustice.
And then they both start going before
the king. No, the child is mine. No, the
child is mine. And Solomon in all his
wisdom cannot discern who is telling the
truth and who is lying.
Let's break this down, you guys. Are
y'all ready?
In this story, there are two women.
Two women.
I want you to notice with me in
Ephesians chapter 5:2 where the Bible
says, "Husbands, love your wives even as
Christ also loved the church and gave
himself for it." I want you to
understand here that in the Bible, a
woman is often used symbolically of a
church. And in light of that analogy,
I'm going to bring that analogy into the
text.
And so what I'm sharing with you beloved
today is I'm using this story to simply
say to you that in the world there are
two types of Christians.
Two types of Christians
both claiming
that they possess the son.
Now, we understand that these two women
may very well represent two churches,
two different types of churches, but for
the sake of our study today, both the
women were in one house. So, we're going
to be talking just about in the church
of God, there are two different types of
Christians, both claiming
to possess the Son. When in reality,
only one
really possesses the Son. Only one
really possesses Jesus Christ. And this
brings us right back to the point we
made a little bit earlier in Matthew
7:21 where the Bible says,
"Not everyone that saith unto me, Lord,
Lord, shall enter into the kingdom of
heaven, but he that doeth the will of my
father which is in heaven. Many will say
to to me in that day, Lord, Lord, have
we not prophesied in thy name? And in
thy name cast out devils, and in thy
name done many wonderful works." And
then will I profess unto them, I never
knew you. Depart from me, you that work
iniquity. There are two types of
Christians in the church and and both
claim to have Jesus but only one really
has Jesus. Only one really has the son.
And remember now Solomon in all his
wisdom cannot tell the difference. Both
women seem sincere. Both women are
probably weeping. Both women seem moved
with passion for the son. But one is
insincere.
Let's talk about it.
The woman that lost her child lost her
child because she was careless.
The text says, let's read it again. And
this woman's child died in the night
because she overlaid it. She slept.
She slept on Jesus.
She slept on the son.
She was careless with her relationship
with Jesus. Many of us, beloved, are
careless in our relationship with
Christ. We're not taking care of him.
We're not taking care of the
relationship the way we are supposed to.
And so what happens is while men slept,
I mean, while we sleep,
it is amazing. While we sleep,
the enemy is able to come in and switch
out Jesus's on us.
First Kings chapter 3 20. Let me read it
again. And she rose at midnight and took
my son from beside me while thine
handmade slept and laid it in her bosom
and laid her dead child in my bosom. And
when I arose in the morning to give my
child suck, behold, it was dead. But be
but when I considered in the morning,
behold, it was not my son which I did
bear. Beloved, we got to be careful. We
have to be careful not to sleep on
Jesus. Because if we do, I guarantee you
the enemy will come in and switch him
out. Switch out a counterfeit Jesus.
The enemy wants to switch Jesuses with
us.
Hold that thought for a moment. Hold
that thought for a moment.
First Kings chapter 3 23. And the other
woman said, "Nay, but the living is my
son, and the dead is thy son. And this
said, no, but the dead is thy son, and
the living is my son." Thus they spake
before the king. Then said the king, the
one said, This is my son that liveth,
and thy son is dead. And the others
said, "Nay, but thy son is the dead, and
mine's the living." And the king said,
"Bring me a sword." And they brought a
sword before the king. And watch this
now. The king said, "Divide the living
child in two and give half to the one
and half to the other."
The woman who's
who did not have a relationship with the
son responds,
"Let it be neither mine nor thine, but
divided."
The woman who did not really possess the
child was content to divide the body.
Let me say it again.
Let me say it again. The woman who did
not have a relationship with the child
was cool
was fine
with half with dividing the body.
Now what does dividing the body mean? It
means there would be a left side of the
body
and a right side of the body. Let's just
look at it like that. A left side of the
body and a right side of the body.
Do you know that in the church today
there are two Jesuses?
There is the left Jesus
and there is the right Jesus.
Are you Are y'all ready? I'm not sure if
you're ready for this, but you're going
to have to be because we're dealing with
some very unfortunate realities
in the church, beloved. There is a left
Jesus and there is a right Jesus.
Many Christians in the church possess
the spirit of this woman who says, "Let
it be divided.
Let it neither be whole. Let it neither
be mine or thine, but just let it be
divided."
So let's talk about left Jesus first
because many of us have accepted a left
Jesus
that that at first seems good. Let's
talk about left Jesus. Come on. So left
Jesus has some very good qualities. Left
Jesus uh h uh lives on verses like
these. Let's go to the screen. Luke 4:1
18 and 19. The spirit of the Lord is
upon me because he has anointed me to
preach the gospel to the poor. He has
sent me to heal the brokenhearted, to
preach deliverance to the captives and
recovering of sight to the blind, to set
at liberty them that are bruised, to
preach the acceptable year of the Lord.
Left Jesus loves the oppressed. Left
Jesus is concerned about about the
oppressed and about those who are
captive. This is very appealing. Left
Jesus is appealing. left. This is left
Jesus's verse. Come on, let's go back to
the screen. Let's go. Matthew chapter
25. Matthew 25:35 and 36. This is left
Jesus for I was hungered and you gave me
meat. I was thirsty and you gave me
drink. I was a stranger and you took me
in. Naked and you clothed me. I was sick
and you visited me. I was in prison and
you came unto me. Left Jesus thrives on
these verses. These verses are verses of
compassion. left. Jesus thrives thrives
on Matthew 25:40. In as much as you've
done it unto the least of these, my
brethren, you have done it unto me.
Isaiah 1:17, learn to do well. Seek
judgment, relieve the oppressed, judge
the fatherless, plead the widow. Plead
the widow. How about this? Uh Micah 6:8.
But he has shown thee, oh man, what is
good. And what does the Lord require of
thee but to do justly and to love mercy
and to walk humbly with thy God. There's
Amos 5:24. Let judgment run down as
waters and righteousness as mighty
streams. And and James 1:27, pure
religion and undefiled before God and
the father is this to visit the
fatherless and widows in their
affliction and to keep him himself
unspotted from the world. And how about
this one? Proverbs 31:8 and 9. Open thy
mouth for the dumb in the cause of all
such are appointed to destruction. Open
thy mouth, judge righteously, and plead
the cause of the poor and the needy.
Beloved,
there are some good things about left
Jesus. If I were to ask you right now,
how many of you are liking how left
Jesus sounds? How many of you would say,
"Man, I love this Jesus." I love left
Jesus. put a one in the chat if you
would say, "Hey man, I this I love this
Jesus."
And and so you would think, well, who
would have a problem with left Jesus?
Left Jesus is good Jesus. But hold on,
there are others in the church
who have right Jesus.
Right Jesus.
You take your half of Jesus and I'm
going to take my half of Jesus. there.
There's some reason that they don't like
left Jesus.
Right Jesus doesn't like left Jesus
and left Jesus doesn't like right Jesus.
Are y'all following me?
Please y'all please just just Okay.
So, please follow along and please
let's not let's not put anyway
guys please be respectful in the chat.
I'm asking you I'm asking you please be
respectful in the chat. No, right Jesus.
Right Jesus.
There are good attributes about right J.
Let's talk about right Jesus. Right
Jesus says stuff like this. Matthew
7:21. Not everyone that saith unto me,
Lord, Lord, shall enter into the kingdom
of heaven, but he that doeth the will of
my father which is in heaven. Right
Jesus is all about doing the right thing
and doing what the word says. Right
Jesus, but as 1 Peter 1:15, but as he
which has called you is holy, so be ye
holy in all manner of conversation
because it is written, "Be ye holy, for
I am holy." Right? Jesus is about living
right. Holiness, right? Jesus loves
verses like these. Hebrews 12:14,
"Follow peace with all men and holiness
without which no man shall see the
Lord." Right? Jesus sounds pretty good
to me, guys. Write Jesus. Here is the
patience of the saints. here they keep
the commandments of God and have the
faith of Jesus. It's about doing right
with right Jesus.
Ecclesiastes 12:13, let us hear the
conclusion of the whole. Yes, that's
right. Thank you, Paul. Let's not put
names out there, please. Right. Jesus
says, let us hear the conclusion of the
whole matter. Fear God and keep his
commandments, for this is the whole duty
of man. That's right, Jesus. Right.
Jesus says, the statutes of the Lord are
right, rejoicing the heart. The
commandments of the Lord is pure,
enlightening the eyes. The fear of the
Lord is clean, enduring forever. The
judgments of the Lord are true and
righteous alltogether.
This is right Jesus. Right Jesus. Right
Jesus.
Hold on.
Pause for a second.
How many of you think right Jesus sounds
pretty good? Put a one in the chat if
you're like, man, this right Jesus, he's
all about business. He sounds good. That
right Jesus sounds good.
Left Jesus sounds good.
Right Jesus sounds good.
But you see beloved, there is a problem
with left Jesus. There is a deep down
dark problem with left Jesus.
Let's talk about left Jesus's problems
first.
You see,
left Jesus isn't too concerned about
obedience.
Left Jesus loves the sinner but is
unconcerned about the sin.
Y'all put a five in the chat if
you you lock in on what I just said.
left Jesus
loves
the sinner
but is not at all concerned about the
sin
left Jesus says ah it's it's not really
a sin is it
left Jesus
ignores verses like these John 811
Jesus said unto her, "Neither do I
condemn thee. Go
and sin
no more." Left Jesus has radical
inclusivity without requiring
repentance.
Left Jesus ignores verses like these.
Fear God and keep his commandments for
this is the whole duty of man. Left
Jesus cares about justice for the
oppressed without accountability for
sin.
left. Jesus is is about mercy but is not
about judgment because he has appointed
a day in which he will judge the whole
world in righteousness by that man whom
he has ordained whereof he giveth
assurance unto all men in that he raised
him up from the dead. Left Jesus says
hey mercy is good but left Jesus isn't
too concerned about judgment.
Left Jesus ignores the fact that you
must be born again. In John 3:es 3-5,
the Bible says, "Jesus answered and said
unto him, verily, verily, I say unto
thee, except a man be born again, he
cannot enter the kingdom of God."
Nicodemus saith unto him, "How can a man
be born when he's old? Can he enter the
second time into his mother's womb and
be born?" Jesus said, "Verily, verily, I
say unto thee, except a man be born of
water and of the spirit,
he cannot enter the kingdom of God."
Left Jesus says, "Hey, you can be
forgiven, but you don't need to be
transformed." left. Jesus
is concerned about feeding the hungry
but ignores the bread of life.
The Bible says in 2 Timothy chapter
2:15, "Study to show thyself approved, a
workman that needeth not be ashamed of
the word of God." Study to show thyself
approved, a workman that needeth not be
ashamed of the word of God. the the the
left Jesus is more concerned with
feeding the hungry with bread than
feeding the hungry with the word.
John chapter 6:35 Jesus said, "I am the
bread of life. He that cometh to me
shall never hunger. He that believeth on
me shall never thirst." Left Jesus
celebrates diversity
without discernment.
Romans 1:25-28, who changed the truth of
God into a lie, and worshiped and served
the creature more than the creator, who
is blessed forever, forever. Amen. For
this cause God gave them up unto vile
affections, for even their women did
change the natural use unto that which
is against nature. And likewise also the
men leaving the natural use of the
woman, burned in their lust one toward
another, men with men working that which
is unseemly. Left Jesus says, "Hey, this
verse doesn't really matter.
Left Jesus is nonjud non-judgmental to
the point of silence.
Left Jesus ignores this verse. Judge not
according to the appearance but judge
righteous judgment.
Are you with me? Are you following? Are
you understand? Left Jesus
has a tolerance for sin that is
disguised as love.
left. Jesus says um
left Jesus ignores Ezekiel 3:18. When I
say unto the wicked, thou shalt surely
die, and thou givest him not warning,
nor nor speaketh to warn the wicked from
his wicked way to save his life, the
same wicked man shall die in his
iniquity, but his blood will I require
at your hand.
left Jesus embraces a social aspect of
the gospel without connecting that
social aspect with the eternal gospel
which says in Revelation 14 6 and 7 I
saw another angel fly in the midst of
heaven having the everlasting gospel to
preach unto them that dwell on the earth
to every nation kindred tongue and
people saying with a loud voice fear God
and give glory to him for the hour of
his judgment is coming and worship him
that made heaven and earth the sea and
the fountains of water
left. Jesus wants peace without the
sword.
When Jesus said, "Think not that I'm
come to send peace on the earth. I came
not to send peace but a sword." You see,
beloved, the problem with left Jesus is
that while left Jesus looks good, he is
not balanced.
Left Jesus is not really Jesus. It just
looks like Jesus.
left Jesus. Left. Okay, let me say it
this way. Right now, you can tell
if you have accepted left Jesus
if in your heart you're kind of
struggling right now with what is being
said about left Jesus.
If you're trying to protect left Jesus,
>> then that might be Jesus actually
speaking to you
because beloved left Jesus is not Jesus.
He may look like Jesus just like the two
women in the story. Hey, he's mine. He's
mine. But one woman was content with
half of Jesus. The other woman was like,
"No, no, no, no, no. I need all of
Jesus.
And so the question now for us is, hey,
do I really have all of Jesus or do I
just have left Jesus? Do I just have
right Jesus? Because just as there is a
dark side to left Jesus, there is a dark
side to right Jesus.
You see,
right Jesus
is a Republican.
Everybody knows that.
Right Jesus is Republican.
Who doesn't know that? Right. Jesus uh
uh isn't too fond of the immigrants.
Right. Jesus doesn't believe racism
exists. Right. Jesus thinks that black
people are in high positions uh that
aren't qualified to be there. Black
Jesus, I'm sorry,
right Jesus is a communist hunter. Right
Jesus is a Marxist hater. Right Jesus is
anti-woke, meaning anything that is
against right Jesus. That's what
anti-woke is. Right Jesus is anti-dei
because right Jesus isn't about
diversity or inclusion or right Jesus
hates critical race theory because white
Jesus a right Jesus I'm sorry right
Jesus
erroneously thinks that critical race
theory teaches that all white people are
just racist
right Jesus is antivaccine
and now right Jesus right Jesus is now
anti- Tylenol
You know that, right?
Do y'all catch what I'm saying? Come on,
put a one in the chat if you're like,
"Oh, hey, I know right Jesus and I know
left Jesus. I've seen them both."
See? See? Let's go. Let's go to the
screen, y'all. Right? Jesus ignores
Right. Jesus ignores this this very
important thing. 1 Corinthians 13:2,
"And though I have the gift of prophecy
and understand all mysteries and all
knowledge, and though I have all faith
so that I can remove mountains and have
not charity, I am nothing." Right? Jesus
doesn't worry about love. Right? Jesus
only thinks about what he calls tough
love.
Right? Jesus is concerned with holiness
without mercy. Let's go back to the
screen where Jesus the real Jesus said,
"Woe unto you scribes and Pharisees,
hypocrites, for you pay tithe of mint
and annis and cumin and have omitted the
weightier matters of the law, judgment,
mercy, and faith. These you ought to
have done, and not to have left the
other undone." Right? Jesus is concerned
about obedience, but doesn't care about
compassion. Matthew 9:13. But go ye and
learn what what this meanth. I will have
mercy and not sacrifice. For I'm not
come to call the righteous, but sinners
to repentance. Right Jesus is all about
the law, but doesn't think too much
about grace, for the law was given by
Moses, but grace and truth came by Jesus
Christ. Right Jesus is concerned about
judgment and doesn't care too much about
forgiveness. So, right Jesus would have
stoned the woman caught in adultery.
Y'all get what I'm saying?
Right Jesus would have stoned the woman
caught in adultery and then rejoiced
about the stoning, rejoiced about the
exposing.
Right? Jesus is more concerned with
religion than he is with relationship.
And so Jesus says, "The real Jesus says,
"This people draweth nigh to me with
their mouth and honorth me with their
lips, but their heart is far from me. In
vain do they worship me, teaching for
doctrines the commandments of men."
Right? Jesus is all about zeal without
knowledge. For I bear them record that
they have a zeal of God, but not
according to knowledge. For they being
ignorant of God's righteousness, and
going about to establish their own
righteousness, have submitted
themselves, have not submitted
themselves unto the righteousness of
God.
Right? Jesus defends
cruelty
in the name
of Jesus.
They shall put you out of the
synagogues. Yay, the time cometh that
whosoever kill you will think he's doing
God's service. And these things they
will do unto you because they have not
known the Father nor known me.
Right? Jesus
doesn't care about righteousness, the
righteousness of Christ.
They ignore these verses. being found in
him, not having my own righteousness,
which is of the law, but that which is
through faith of Christ, the
righteousness which is of God by faith.
What I'm trying to tell you, beloved, is
that in a certain sense,
we have created God in our own image.
We have taken Jesus and said, "I am
content with left Jesus or I am content
with right Jesus." And now we literally
go through life thinking that Jesus is
actually in heaven a Republican,
in heaven a Democrat,
in heaven a leftist, in heaven a
rightist. We are, we literally believe
with all our How can you not see that
Jesus is a Republican? I I don't
understand. What are you, what are you
talking? Oh, are you not a Christian?
You must not be a Christian cuz you
don't know that Jesus is MAGA.
Don't you get that?
We have created Jesus in our own image.
So, so what's happening is
that people are walking around with half
of Jesus.
And if you have half of Jesus, you
really have none of Jesus.
Remember how the the the the text said
in Solomon how how he was before the ark
of the covenant? That's significant, you
guys, because I want you to notice
something about the ark of the covenant.
In Exodus 25:10-11, listen to this.
Exodus 25:10-11 the Bible says, "And
they shall make an ark of and wood.
Two cubits and a half shall be the
length thereof, and a cubit and a half
the breadth thereof, and a cubit and a
half the height thereof. And thou shalt
overlay it with pure gold within and
without shalt thou overlay it, and make
it a crown of gold round.
And thou shalt put into the ark of the
testimony which I shall give thee. Thou
shalt put into the ark the testimony
which I shall give thee.
and thou shalt make a mercy seat of pure
gold.
Let's stop right there.
Do you know that the ark of the
covenant,
that part of the ark of the covenant is
the mercy seat? Here's what happens,
beloved. Left Jesus says, "Give me the
mercy seat." Right? Jesus says, "Give me
the ark." You cannot separate that
article of furniture.
You can't do that. To do that is to be
content with half the child.
God demands justice and he also demands
mercy. God demands left and right of
Jesus.
Our appeal should not be give me half of
Jesus. It should be give me Jesus.
All of Jesus. All of Jesus. Many of us
are content with half of Jesus.
Many of us in the church are guilty of
worshiping right Jesus or left Jesus.
Not understanding that when you take the
good attributes of right Jesus and the
good attributes of left Jesus and bring
them together that is when you actually
have Jesus. So to have Jesus is a denial
of the right Jesus who says yes justice
and this is wrong and this is right
without caring about the oppressed. That
is not the the Jesus you have that
doesn't care about the immigrant, about
the oppressed, about the needy, that is
not Jesus. And the Jesus you have who
who cares about the oppressed and the
immigrant and all those things, but
hates righteousness, doesn't doesn't
expose sin, that is not Jesus.
And if you are content with half of
Jesus, you do not have Jesus at all.
And so,
and so
the king says in his wisdom, what? Come
on, y'all. Come on. Listen to this. The
king says in his wisdom, "Bring me a
sword."
Yes.
Just let me clap over here by myself for
a moment, y'all. Bring me a sword. Now,
listen y'all. Solomon is not about to
kill the child.
That's not who he is.
The reason he says, "Bring me a sword,"
is because the sword he knows is going
to reveal
who is the true mother and who isn't.
Come on, y'all. Come on. Come on. Come
on.
Bring me a sword.
Hebrews 4:12, for the word of God, for
the word of God. For the word of God,
for the word of God, for the word of God
is quick and powerful and sharper than
any two-edged sword, piercing even to
the dividing aunderder of soul and
spirit, and of the joints and marrow,
and is a discerner of the thoughts and
intents of the heart. Solomon knows I
got to get I got to get I got to get to
the to the thoughts and the intents of
these two women. So bring me a sword
because the word of God when fully
accepted reveals who is the true and who
is the false. Who really has a
relationship with Jesus and who doesn't?
And listen
Jesus is not condemning us here. He's
not saying ah you only have half half
Jesus you're lost. What he's trying to
show us is listen, you are walking
around with half Jesus thinking you're
converted and you're not. And I'm
revealing it to you so that you can get
all of Jesus.
This is exactly what's happening in the
Christian world today, beloved. So,
watch this. The sword is the word of
God. The sword reveals what's really in
our hearts.
The sword is the whole word of God. Acts
20 27. Acts 20 27. Note what the text
says. For I have not shunned to declare
unto you all the counsel of God. All the
counsel of God. You see, beloved, the
real Jesus de the real Jesus is about
all the counsel of God. Left Jesus only
likes the verses about oppression and
being kind and being sweet. Right Jesus
only likes the verses about judgment and
yes, abortion is wrong and all these
things. Left Jesus wants to point out
everything that is wrong. Right Jesus
wants to point out all the all the
things that should be good. But beloved,
if we're not listen,
left Jesus,
left Jesus claims to be woke.
[Music]
left. Jesus,
claims to be woke
but is asleep to the word of God.
Right Jesus is anti-woke.
Meaning right Jesus is also asleep.
Because I need you to understand to be
anti-woke, to be anti-awwake is to be
asleep. Right? Jesus is sleeping and
left Jesus is sleeping.
And what the church needs now more than
ever is to present to the world a
picture of a Jesus
who is not left Jesus and is not right
Jesus.
And I used to think
that of all people, our church would be
the church that could say, "Hey guys,
listen. This is what's good about left
Jesus. This is what's good about right
Jesus." And in actuality, the real Jesus
is a combination of these things. But
no, in the church too, we have said,
"Hey, divide the child. Give me left
Jesus and I'm I'll be on my way. Give me
right Jesus and I'll be on my way.
There's another title to this message
which I cannot say yet, but I will say
as we get to that part.
We're getting there and I hope y'all are
sitting down.
Come on. First Kings chapter 3 26 and
27. Watch what happens. Then spake the
woman whose the living child was unto
the king, for her bowels yearned upon
her son. And she said, "Oh my lord, give
her the living child and in no wise slay
it." Then said the king and answered, or
then answered the king, and said, "Give
her the living child and in no wise slay
it. She is the mother thereof." Listen,
the true mother would rather sacrifice
herself than see the body the body the
body divided.
The true mother
was willing to sacrifice herself then
she would rather sacrifice herself than
see the body of the child. the body
divided.
Solomon's call for the sword was not to
to kill the child, to divide the body.
It was to reveal who truly cares about
the son.
And you know what's amazing? When the
true mother said, "No, don't harm the
child. Give her the child." Oh man, that
it is her child
and the woman is willing to lose her
child that the child may live.
In this very thing, listen to me. In
this very thing, the woman actually
reveals justice in her cry.
Justice means giving each their due. So
the woman, the true mother acknowledges,
if the child must live, if the child
must live, even if it costs me my
rights, let justice be done for the
child.
The the true mother even in that cry was
revealing mercy because she could have
said, "Hey, divide the child and at
least give me half." But in her mind, no
mer this child needs mercy right now.
His life is on the line. And if it
requires me losing what rightfully
belongs to me, I would rather mercy than
have the child die.
You guys understand this. This woman is
reflecting the whole Jesus. She's
reflecting the Jesus of justice, the
Jesus of mercy. She's reflecting in her
action exactly what Jesus is, who is
justice and mercy met in one.
You do understand beloved that the wages
of sin is death. You understand that
according to Romans chapter 6 verse 23.
See it on the screen. The wages of sin
is death. And you do understand that a
sword was headed to us. But Jesus said
no no no.
Let me take the sword.
Zechariah 13:7. Awake oh sword against
my shepherd and against the man that is
my fellow. Sayith the Lord of hosts,
"Smite the shepherd, and the sheep shall
be scattered, and I will turn my hand
upon the little ones." Jesus took the
sword on our behalf.
Come on, y'all. Jesus took the sword on
our behalf so that we would not die, so
that we would not be divided. And if he
was willing to die on our behalf, that
that the body not be divided. How dare
we?
How dare we?
How dare we MAGA Adventists? How dare we
leftist Adventist? How dare we
divide the body that Christ died for to
bring together?
How dare we? The Bible says in Isaiah
53:5 and 6, "But he was wounded for our
transgressions. He was bruised for our
iniquities. The chastisement of our
peace was upon him, and with his stripes
we are healed. All we like sheep have
gone astray and have turned everyone his
own way. And the Lord laid on him
the iniquity of us all."
This is why, beloved, we're told in 1
John 4:19, "We love him because what? He
first loved us,
a false Christian.
The Christians that are content
with half Jesus, God is trying to speak.
God's trying to speak.
He's trying to show us what is in our
hearts that we do not even know or
understand is there
because the heart is deceitfully wicked.
who can know it.
He's trying to appeal to us. There are
so many of us that that are in this
world where evil is growing by the day.
We are we are becoming engrossed and
and taking our eyes off of Jesus.
You guys listen to me.
The body should not be divided
over vaccines
or over race.
There is nothing that should divide the
body of Christ.
And you can almost see the hypocrisy
when a when a call was made last year to
divide the body because of religious
liberty and vaccines and blah blah blah.
There were people who were
because the church is an apostasy
anyway. The church is not the church is
the church is is it's no longer the
voice of of God on earth. And and and
there's corruption and and and and there
were these ju just hey it what's the big
deal?
Whole conferences are going to fall.
And last year when I said, "Hey, no, no,
no, no, no, no. Wrong move, you don't
know what you're talking about." And now
now
in in in light of certain events that
have taken place over the last several
weeks where you now have this issue of
race being brought up in the church and
questions and talk of, you know, should
we divide? Should we have, you know, a
black conference or a white conference?
I say, no, that's still not the answer.
I mean,
wow, what a what a slip up. Black
conferences and white conferences. I'll
get to that in a moment. Should we
separate based on on this? And I'm
saying no. The same people who were
cheering back then and saying, "Oh, this
is boldness. This is courage. We need to
stand." are saying, "Well, how can you?
This is this is divisive and this is a"
And you know what? Trust me. Trust me.
Guess what's going to happen? Those who
follow right Jesus are going to be like,
"Well, you see the difference between
that and this is."
And those who follow left Jesus who are
cheering this on will say, "Well, the
difference between this and that was,"
and I'm telling you, I'm telling you,
you guys,
dividing the body
is never the answer. That's what
Satan wants to do.
Last year when people were talking about
we need to boycott the GC and and we're
going to take our tithe and divert it
and people were cheering it and I said
no that's wrong. We we no we and
how dare you.
How dare you?
And when I say the same thing now,
regardless of what I believe is an
actual issue that needs to be addressed
in our church, I'm saying still the
issue needs to be addressed. Let's come
together and address the issue. But no,
division is not the answer.
And when I see that that people are
willing to divide and you got to
understand beloved, we might be we we
are still a church but the the division
is happening on a micro level because
people are splitting friendships. You
know how many you know how many friends
I've lost that I don't even know I've
lost yet?
friends who have lost because because
they thought I was worshiping left
Jesus.
Anytime I spoke about, you know, we got
to stand for justice. Oh, you're left
Jesus. You don't believe that that you
know that that this is wrong or this is
wrong. And I'm like, when did I ever say
that? I don't believe this is wrong.
This is wrong. No, I it was just you're
left Jesus. You're right, Jesus.
And and so this division happening on
this micro level is people cutting
people off. I don't talk with them no
more. Why? cuz she's left Jesus. He's
left Jesus. He's right Jesus. She's
right Jesus. And people just stop
talking.
Sometimes you don't even know that
you've been unfriended till you're
running through your Facebook one day
and you're like, "Wait a minute. We were
Oh, we're not friends. Wow, man.
The division is happening on a micro
level, revealing that we are just like
the woman in this story.
Martin Luther King
said this. He said, "It is appalling
that the most segregated hour of
Christian America is 11:00 on Sunday
morning.
You see, beloved, we don't just have
left Jesus and right Jesus. There is
also black Jesus and white Jesus.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. The full title
of this message is actually left Jesus,
right? Jesus, black Jesus, white Jesus.
What Martin Luther King said way back
then is still true today.
We still have black Jesus and white
Jesus.
Ellen White said something that that's
really quite concerning.
Let me read to you what she said. I'm
just going to put them up on the screen.
Three or four quotes. In 1895, she said,
"Slavery will be revived again will be
revived in the southern states, for the
spirit of slavery still lives."
She also said, "The same spirit that
held the colored people in slavery is
not dead, but alive today and ready to
spring into action."
Once again,
she said, "In the South, the spirit of
slavery is not eradicated. It has only
been smothered for a short time." This
is 1899.
She also said in an interview, this
interview was recorded 1907.
She said, "Slavery, there will be
slavery just as verily 1907, you guys.
There will be slavery just as verily as
it has been only upon a basis that is
more favorable and secure to white
people. PT man who she was speaking to
responded by saying more secure because
they do not feed they do not have to
feed the negroes or care for them. Then
if the negro has got outside that
district or if he is loafing and not
working, they can put him in the chain
gang for a year.
You understand what Ellen White was
saying here? Ellen White was prophesying
the promotion
of systemic racism
where slavery would just change its face
and would be more favorable, she says,
to the white people. This is Ellen White
speaking, y'all. Not me. Not me.
Not all white people, she said. It's not
what she's talking about, but those whom
racism dwells in their hearts.
And the reason I bring this up, beloved,
is because because
I praise God
that the Adventist Church is one of the
most diverse
churches in the world. How many of you
want to put a seven in the chat for
that? put a seven in the chat that you
say we praise God that the Adventist
church is one of the most diverse
churches in the world,
racially
diverse.
I praise God for that.
But I also need to talk about Lucy
Bayard,
who in 1943
became seriously ill and was taken to a
hospital, Washington Sanitarium,
um, in Tacoma Park.
And because she was light-skinned, they
thought she was white.
And then
when they found out she was black, they
told her that they could not serve her.
systemic racism
in the Adventist church
in 1943.
And what happened is that they she had
to go to another hospital and then she
actually died sometime later, short time
later. and her death was blamed
on
this racism.
And
as a result of this,
the body
was split.
We had the introduction of regional
conferences
because
of systemic racism
within the Adventist church.
That was 1944.
The body
was split.
The body was divided.
And we are now in 2025.
And what I'm saying to you, beloved, is
we cannot do this any longer.
The body of Christ must come together.
What that looks like, I don't know. I
don't have the answers. But here's what
I do know.
We cannot testify of the love of Jesus.
You understand? You see what's happened
in the last couple of weeks. You see how
race tensions are are are right they're
right there under the carpet.
And if we are not willing
to deal with the division,
the body will remain divided between
left Jesus, right Jesus, black Jesus,
white Jesus.
And then Ellen White has a statement
here that is a rebuke to us all.
Here's what she says.
In fact, let me read Genesis 1:26 verse
and then I'm going to read what she
says. In Genesis 1:26, the Bible says,
"And God said, ' Let us make man in our
image, after our likeness, and let them
have dominion over the fish of the sea
and the fowl of the air." Do you
understand, beloved, that what we have
done, what many of us have done is we
have said, "Let us make God in our image
and after our likeness."
Absolutely. Fathom.
Absolutely. Please understand, please
understand that the the start of
regional conferences was not black
people just saying we're going to go
start our own thing. We were black
people were begging for integration
and the response was
and this is the legacy that we that we
carry right now. It's a shameful legacy.
It's a shameful legacy. Here's what
Ellen White said,
and this is good news and bad news.
And I'm going to close this up, you
guys.
She said, "It will be impossible to
adjust all matters regarding the color
question in accordance with the Lord's
order until," Let me stop right there.
You guys, did you hear that just now?
Did you hear that just now?
She said it will be impossible to adjust
all matters regarding the color question
in accordance with the Lord's order
until beloved that is good news.
Did you hear? Put in one in the chat if
you understand how good how good of the
news that is.
It will be impossible to adjust all
matters regarding the color question in
accordance with the Lord's order until
meaning that she saw it happening. She
said something is going to happen that
then it will happen.
The question is oh by the way yes right
Jesus hates the UN too. I forgot about
that. Right Jesus hates the UN.
You you guys the caricature of left
Jesus and right Jesus it just becomes
unfortunately so
laughable if it wasn't so sad
the social gospel.
What is that?
Did not Jesus say take care of your
neighbors, love others? How can right
Jesus degrade that as oh it's a social
gospel?
Are we not supposed to demonstrate the
beauty of the harmony of working for our
neighbors while also preaching the three
angels messages?
Have we not been called to be to call
sin out as it is and yet still be
merciful and gracious and kind and
loving and empathetic.
Let's go back to the statement.
It will be impossible to adjust all
matters regarding the color question in
accordance with the Lord's order until
those who believe the truth are so
closely united with Christ that they are
one with him.
Both the white and the colored members
of our churches need to be converted.
There are some of both classes who are
unreasonable
and when the color question is agitated
they manifest unsanctified
unconverted traits of character.
Quarrelome elements are easily aroused
in those who because they have never
learned to wear the yoke of Christ are
opinionated and obstinate. In such self
clamors with an unsanctified
determination for the supremacy.
Do y'all see what she just said?
The reason the color question still
exists in our church is because whenever
it's brought up, there are many who want
to deny it that it even exists. And
there are others
who through anger don't even want to
talk about it.
It just is what it is.
There's resentment.
Ellen White says that we need to be
converted
because when we are converted, we can
actually then deal with the question
and left Jesus will disappear from the
church and right Jesus will disappear
from the church and black Jesus will
disappear from the church and white
Jesus will disappear from the church and
we will we will be left with just Jesus.
Just Jesus.
All I want is Jesus. Not left Jesus. Not
right Jesus. Not black Jesus. Not white
Jesus. Jesus.
Jesus who loves everybody. Jesus who
loves the left, who loves the right, who
loves the black, who loves the white.
Jesus, the actual Jesus.
God is going to keep bringing us around
to this until we get it right. Why?
Because because
our closing statement,
Christ is waiting with longing desire
for the manifest manifestation of
himself in his church. Do y'all see it
on the screen?
Let me read it again. Christ is waiting
with longing desire for the
manifestation of himself in his church.
It's not up on the screen. I need y'all
to see this when with your own eyes.
All right. Maybe my slide is messed up.
Slide team.
All right. I'll just read it in your
hearing.
Christ is waiting with longing desire
for the manifestation of himself in his
church.
When the character of Christ shall be
perfectly reproduced in his people, then
he will come to claim them as his own.
And here's what I want y'all to
understand.
Right now,
we're told that when the character of
Christ I I'm hoping they can get it up
on the screen. I'm not sure what's going
on, but we're told that Christ is
waiting for us to reflect his character.
But here's what's happening.
We all have different views of the
character of Christ.
So people are are are are reflecting
right Jesus and other people are
reflecting left Jesus and other people
are reflecting black Jesus and other
people are refle reflecting white Jesus.
And so what happens is that the picture
that is forming of Jesus right now is is
a confusing picture.
Before we can get the the character of
Christ reproduced so that when he looks
in the mirror, he sees himself, we all
have to know what Jesus we're
worshiping.
My appeal to you Christians of the
world,
Christians out there in the other
denominations, Christians in our church,
stop reflecting the Jesus you have
created in your own image.
There is not a right Jesus and there is
not a left Jesus. There is Jesus.
There is Jesus.
There is not a black Jesus. There is not
a white Jesus. There is Jesus.
Give me Jesus.
And so right now, I'm going to make a
special appeal.
Right now, I'm going to ask you to get
rid of left Jesus.
And I'm going to ask you who have right
Jesus to make a commitment to get rid of
right Jesus. And what I'm going to do
right now is I'm going to ask you to
respond by putting in the chat L for
today I give up left Jesus and R for
today I give up right Jesus. Please
let's put that in the chat. That's my
appeal. You may not want to out yourself
as who you really believed in left Jesus
or you really believed in right Jesus.
But it's okay.
It's okay. Be like the woman who really
had the son. She was unwilling to let
the body be divided. She was willing to
be seen as wrong that the child might
live. I want you to put that L in the
chat for saying, "Listen, no more left
Jesus for me." R in the chat for saying,
"No more right Jesus for me. I want all
of Jesus." Lord, reintroduce me to who
you are. Help me not to go along with
the painted picture of a right Jesus or
the painted picture of a left Jesus.
Give me Jesus.
Help me to know that I can acknowledge
that racism is a very real thing in the
world today. And also at the same time
say, "Hey, the answer to this is not in
do this to the government and do that."
But in the gospel, help me to know that
I can do those two things. Help me to
know that I can acknowledge that I can
acknowledge that I can acknowledge these
things that are wrong over here, but
also these things that are right over
here. Help me to know that I can be
merciful and loving to the stranger and
also stand up for for what I believe is
right here or there. That two things can
be true at one time.
Help me to stop demonizing
Right Jesus demonizes and left Jesus
demonizes. Help me to understand. Right.
Jesus hates his enemies.
Get them. The wicked Democrats. I've
seen I've seen the statements.
How do you call a whole group of people
wicked? How do you do that and be a
Christian?
I believe I believe that that there
there there are church bodies
that are full of error and you will
never hear me say the wicked Catholics
or the wicked Protestants. You'll never
hear that come out my mouth. But we're
comfortable with saying the wicked
Republicans or the wicked Democrats as a
Christian.
You see, right Jesus and left Jesus
are really selffocused.
The actual Jesus
loves people so much that he's willing
to die even for his enemies.
This woman when she said to the king,
"Give her the child." She could have
been killed
because what she was saying to the king
was, "All right, all right. I'm the
guilty one. I'm the guilty one. Yeah.
Yeah. I I stole the child." And she
could have been killed. She was willing
to look like a criminal, like a liar,
like a thief, like a kidnapper.
because her love for the child was so
Listen y'all, I'm I'm closing. I'm
closing. I promise you
what motivated this woman is that the
child had been formed within her.
If it's not your child, you don't care.
If it's not your child, you can be
callous. If it's not your child, you
don't have the same kind of love for it.
This woman was was connected to the
child because it had been formed within
her. Beloved, if Christ is not in you,
you will be content
with a divided body. You will push for a
divided body. You will glorify a divided
body. you will amplify and talk and and
bring up all the things that that show
and that get people on one side of that
divided body. Come on. We got to we got
to be against the other side. There's
going to be a shaking and all that all
those people are going to be shaken out.
Us against them. Us against them. Us
against them. When we have this us
against them mentality, beloved, we are
missing the point.
It is not us against them, beloved. It
is us against spiritual wickedness in
high places. And our role is to tell the
atheists and to tell the agnostics and
to tell the Protestants and to tell the
Catholics and to tell the people at the
UN and to tell the people in the
government, guess what? The devil is
trying to deceive us all by telling us
it's us versus you, us versus them. Here
is the devil's real plot. But now we're
just getting caught up in left Jesus,
right Jesus, left Jesus, right Jesus,
left Jesus, right Jesus. And we're
proud. And we get in our corners with
our right Jesus friends or our left
Jesus friends. We're like, see those
left Jesusers, those right Jesusers.
Beloved, listen.
Jesus is waiting with longing desire for
the manifestation of himself. Not left
Jesus. Himself, not right Jesus.
himself, not black Jesus, himself, not
white Jesus. And then when that happens,
he will come to claim his own. Heavenly
Father,
I am praying again that our church
will revisit the past, will write the
wrongs. Lord, if we have to call a
10-day meeting, like I said two weeks
ago,
if we have to call a 10-day meeting
where our church comes together and we
address the issues that we have been
sweeping under the rug
for the purpose of uniting the body,
truly uniting the body.
Lord, let it be.
We need a unified front
and we are too busy using the sword to
cut one another in half. Forgive us Lord
for manifesting the spirit of the woman
who said divide it. Let it neither be
mine nor thine but divide it. Forgive us
for worshiping left Jesus, right Jesus,
black Jesus, white Jesus. Lord
give us Jesus
and in his name we pray. Amen. And amen.
May God bless you. May God take this
message
and search our hearts.
and may we bring the body
together the way that the Lord would
have us to do.
God bless you. We're going to put the
chat the the uh the link for the
afterglow discussion. We will be on
mighty networks. Uh you are all free to
join us. um we we fellowship, we talk
about the Sabbath school, we talk about
the sermon, and so it's a chance that
everyone gets to um to uh
uh fellowship together. And I'm going to
ask one more thing. If there's any of
you who
do not know Jesus
and you want to get to know him better,
you want to get to understand his word,
you want to get to know Jesus,
I'm going to ask you, we're going to put
this up on the screen if we can.
Want you to connect with our Bible
worker. Um, let's see if we can get that
up in the screen or get it in the link.
If there's anyone that wants to be
baptized because you feel the Lord
calling you to give your life fully to
Christ, I'm going to invite you to reach
out to that same address once we get it
up on the screen. And um and if you just
want to study again to get to know the
word of God better or to give your life
to Christ, reach out
into his everlasting arms. Amen.
>> Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.
[Music]
Thank you.